Everyone can be everything now. PMs can
ship code, designers can write PRDs,
engineers can product, and there's this
confusion and frustration of what is my
job anymore.
>> Anytime a new technology comes along,
you go through a storming phase before
you go through the forming phase of
things. We are in the middle of that
right now. [music] I don't think that
means we should put AI back into the box
and say let's not use it.
>> If we all become builders, will we still
need separate functions?
>> I still see a craft excellence that's
really important that [music] I don't
think is going away anytime soon. I
still find great engineering to be
scarce, great data science to be scarce,
great creativity to be scarce.
>> If you look at the early culture deck of
Netflix, high agency, autonomy, paying
top of market, this is what I hear
constantly now from how the top AI labs
operate.
>> Netflix's culture has always been
excellence as an operating system. It's
a resistance [music] to do the thing
that a lot of bigger companies would do
and to feel comfortable in that
discomfort very often.
>> What are the ingredients to make this
happen?
>> Talent density is the non-negotiable,
being very comfortable with risk-taking
in cases where things are not going
well, not assume that process is going
to fix it.
>> What have you added to the career
ladders within this AI world?
>> more systems thinkers, people who can
look across all the business domains and
abstract that [music] to here's the
building blocks we're going to need.
>> How do people learn this?
>> Small trick, each problem you're trying
to solve, step out one [music] click to
the what am I assuming is true about the
broader space.
>> Today my guest is Elizabeth Stone,
product and technology officer at
Netflix. This is Elizabeth's second
visit to the podcast. Her first visit,
when she was just a CTO, was for the
longest time one of the most popular
episodes of this podcast. You'll soon
see why this is such a killer
conversation because when we chatted two
and a half years ago, AI was only
starting to emerge. [music] And as a
long time head of engineering and
product and data science, Elizabeth has
such a unique perspective on where
things [music] are heading and what's
worth paying attention to. Prior to
Netflix, Elizabeth was VP of Science at
Lyft, Chief Operating Officer at Nuna,
[music] an economist at The Analysis
Group, and a trader at Merrill Lynch.
Before we get into it, don't forget to
check out Lenny's Product Pass dot com
for an entire year free of the hottest
and best crafted AI products in the
world available exclusively to Lenny's
newsletter subscribers. With that, I
bring you Elizabeth Stone.
Elizabeth, thank you so much for being
here and welcome back to the podcast.
>> Thank you. I'm honored to be here. Once
and now twice.
>> That's right. That's a rare a rare treat
for me. I don't know if you know this,
but your first visit to the podcast,
your episode ended up being my second
most popular episode. You're right
behind Brian Chesky for the longest
time.
>> Well, I I I'm pleasantly surprised and
also mildly competitive of how
[clears throat] do I get to the first
spot? But I'll set that aside for now.
>> That's This is our This is our shot.
>> Bri- Brian's amazing, so I'll let that
one go.
>> Yeah, he is uh and then there's just
like all these fancy AI people that are
just coming, you know, coming in hot.
>> [laughter]
>> Um so, it's been 2 and 1/2 years at this
point. A lot's changed.
Uh obviously AI, something AI is
allowing uh people to do is everyone can
kind of be everything now. This idea of
PMs can ship code, designers can write
PRDs, and engineers can product, and
everyone's everything. There's a bunch
of
elements to this conversation. One is
that I've heard from people that there's
also this kind of confusion and
frustration of like what is my job
anymore? Like what am I responsible for
as a PM, as a designer? Is that
something you've experienced?
>> I hear it within Netflix, for sure.
I think anytime a new technology comes
along, especially one that's as
transformative as GenAI,
you go through a storming phase before
you go through the forming phase of
things. And I think we are in the middle
of that right now.
I don't think that means we should put
AI back into the box and say let's not
use it cuz this is kind of this is
complicating all of our preconceived
notions about our roles,
but I do think it means we have to be
much more thoughtful about how do we get
the benefits while reducing the costs.
I think it's a great thing that people
are experimenting with how can I develop
an idea faster, prototype an idea, put
together an initial set of code that
would allow us to test it.
Do I believe that means anyone should be
shipping code to production?
That everyone should actually be doing
everything? Probably not. But I think
that it's good for people to be
exploring what's possible. And then,
like I mentioned earlier, the benefit of
having product and tech teams together
is that if the business problem is
clear, I think it's okay and it's
healthy for there to be some fluidity in
the roles that people play because
instead of having to wait for the
engineering team to be ready to be able
to prototype something, product and
design can move faster on it. But they
should still work with their engineering
partner to think through how should we
productize this? How do we scale it?
What are the guardrails for it? So, I
don't think it makes the functional
expertise obsolete. I think it means
that teams have to be more comfortable
with maybe this helps us move faster in
a certain direction. From an
organizational perspective, things I
think about to make this
more coherent or less frustrating
are some of the things that have to be
in place for us to get the benefits
rather than the costs. So, that includes
clarity on source of truth data,
guardrails on shipping code to
production or testing before we make
large changes,
thinking about opportunities where we
can trust the output of AI versus we
should have a process or review that
helps us check that we're getting high
quality outcomes.
And the importance of reiterating that
humans are still responsible
for what happens. So, it can be that an
agent wrote the code or I helped to do
an analysis when that's not really my
background, but it doesn't make it
doesn't
make people not have the responsibility
that comes with what they've created.
So, I think the investing in some of
those core infrastructure and practices
and reiterating the accountability and
responsibility for the outcomes helps to
balance some of like what's possible
with what we should actually be doing.
>> This episode is brought to you by our
season's presenting sponsor WorkOS. What
do OpenAI and Vercel,
Replit, Sierra, Clay, and hundreds of
other winning companies all have in
common? They are all powered by WorkOS.
If you're building a product for the
enterprise, you've felt the pain of
integrating single sign-on, SCIM, RBAC,
audit logs, and other features [music]
required by large companies. WorkOS
turns those deal blockers into drop-in
APIs with a modern developer platform
built specifically for B2B SaaS.
>> [music]
>> Literally every startup that I'm an
investor in that starts to expand
upmarket ends up working with WorkOS.
And that's because they are the best.
Whether you are seed-stage startup
trying to land your first enterprise
customer or unicorn expanding globally,
WorkOS is the fastest path to becoming
enterprise ready and unlocking growth.
It's essentially Stripe for enterprise
features. Visit workos.com to get
started or just hit up their Slack where
they have actual engineers waiting to
answer your questions. WorkOS allows you
to build faster with delightful APIs,
comprehensive docs, and a smooth
developer experience. Go to workos.com
to make your app enterprise ready today.
>> What's really awesome about having you
back on the podcast is
we chatted like before AI was a massive
transformation in the world. So, it's a
really cool arc that we can explore
here. This the shift that we've all gone
through.
>> Mhm.
>> Coming back to the roles of the product
and inch team, I'm curious
how much these roles have changed in the
last two and a half years. If you think
about product engineering,
uh design, data science, user research,
which roles have
changed most? Which roles have changed
least? Like, what's most different in
the last two since two and a half years
ago?
>> So, you've mentioned some of the things,
so I'll I'll reiterate them and then
maybe build. So, I have found that PMs,
designers,
data scientists are able to get farther
in the product development life cycle
before engineering really needs to be
front of the line in unlocking things
than was true a couple years ago.
I say that with some caution because,
like we were talking about, I don't
think it's great to all of a sudden have
thousands of prototypes if they're not
aimed at this is an important problem to
solve for the business
and the engineering partners are aware
that we're solving that problem and that
designers and product managers are going
to take the lead in starting to shape
the idea, but it's not working in a
vacuum and it's not throwing a bunch of
spaghetti at the wall to see what
sticks.
But when it's the right problem,
approached in a thoughtful way with some
alignment on that, I've seen product
design data science move faster in the
direction of let's get to something
that's testable on this hypothesis.
So, that's prototyping, that's writing
code. The other thing I've seen as being
very valuable is we have a lot of
information
running around in the virtual walls of
Netflix. We have experiments we've run
over decades. We have insights from
consumers. We have input from
stakeholders across the business. And
that was a problem that really presented
a challenge of like, how do we get the
most out of that long history of
knowledge and learnings to say, let's
apply that to the problem we've got now
to move faster in this is a promising
path or this is something that we've
learned something about and we could
leverage here.
And AI is very powerful at distilling
information,
looking across a broad set of things,
doing an analysis around it, getting to
the core of here's some insights to
start with. I I would hesitate to rely
on that exclusively, but I think it's a
head start. And I find even in my own
work day-to-day, instead of
sending an email that disrupts someone
of like, remind me what research did we
do in what year and what was the
question and what was the test we ran? I
can find that almost instantly. Then I
can form my own, here's what I find
interesting about this and I've now
skipped a couple steps towards is there
something actionable here? So that's
data analysis, it's modeling, it's
distillation of information and I'm
seeing more people do that to your
original question. So instead of that
needing to be
only the experts who were here for 20
years and saw every experiment or know
where to find it, we're now able to do
that faster within product and tech
across all functions and a big unlock
for us is our business stakeholders
sitting in finance and content and
advertising can do that as well and then
bring back an initial hypothesis where
they want to work more deeply with the
data scientists and engineer and so on.
So there's something there about the the
hypothesis generation, prototyping,
thinking deeply about problems that
feels like it's accelerating and that
functions are able to do that in a more
fluid way.
But I still see comparative strengths.
So data scientists are still going to be
experts at can we trust this data? Are
we interpreting it the right way? What's
the data versus judgment that we should
be applying here? A product manager is
still going to be exceptional at saying,
have we really framed the what of this?
Like the problem we're solving in the
right way? An engineer still has a craft
around the how. How does this scale?
What does high quality look like? What
problems is this going to create for us
based on how we build and deploy
something? So I still see the nuggets of
that comparative advantage. It's just
that we're able to move more fluidly in
a lot of steps that normally we would
have blockers on.
>> There's so much interesting stuff here.
One is this last point you made is
something I've been thinking about. If
we all become builders, will we still
need separate functions? There's this
like member of technical staff trend
that is happening in the past where it's
like, all right, we don't have a title,
you could be anything.
You don't have to be in a bucket. What
you're saying here is you believe we
will continue to have specialties,
product person, engineer, data science,
designer.
While they do more of other functions,
there's still a lot of value in Tell me
if I'm hearing you correct in having the
specific discipline and skill and
background.
>> I still see a craft excellence that's
really important in the disciplines that
I don't think is going away anytime
soon. Even if there's fluidity or
blurring of the work across the
functional lines. It goes back to what I
mentioned earlier of you still have
humans who have to make sure that what
we're doing makes sense. We're solving
the right problems in a way that is best
for Netflix members or business
stakeholders.
And that if I talk to an engineer, a
data scientist, a designer,
yes, they speak more languages now than
they used to because they have the
benefit of these AI tools.
But there's still something that is not
replaceable
when I think about the craft and how
they think about what good looks like.
And that feels true across all levels
and you know, I still find great
engineering to be scarce. Great data
science to be scarce. Great creativity
to be scarce. So I
yes, some things are easier, but that
hasn't dissolved in my mind.
>> Are there functions that you are finding
you are hiring more of? Like the pie
chart pie expanding
say for engineering or PM or design or
something and then functions you're need
less of with AI tool and LLMs rising.
>> Not sure that it matches exactly to
functions, but I can tell you
what we're having we're seeing more of,
we need more of.
We need more systems thinkers
in a world with AI.
That looks a little bit different across
functions, but I could play out a couple
examples. So,
in our core infrastructure team at
Netflix in central engineering,
a lot of what made Netflix successful
over time was that
local teams with specific business
problems could move fast to deliver.
They very often were not feeling like
they needed to be on a central paved
path. They built the stack that they
needed to solve the problem and have the
impact.
In a world of AI with agents operating
across multiple systems,
wanting source of truth data, the
importance of having preferred paved
paths that
get the most of the benefits and produce
some guardrails so we can make sure
we're doing good work,
common infrastructure, common paved
paths, solving problems once with a core
set of capabilities becomes more
important.
So, we are hiring more people who can
look across all the business domains and
abstract that to here's the building
blocks we're going to need in a world
with AI. So, that's one of the lenses,
but also just with a lens of what got
Netflix here doesn't get Netflix there.
And we're going to have to have a
stronger set of infrastructure to move
quickly in this future.
So, that means that engineering profiles
are more distributed systems, more
infrastructure, more of that system
thinking mindset than a a local business
expertise. Though, of course, we still
have people who are deep in
personalization and advertising and
content delivery. So, it's more
something additive for us to have that
core infrastructure and systems
thinking.
If I take another example, like design,
it's extremely important that our
experience design team is developing
templates and again systems thinking for
what does great user design look like at
Netflix so that they can enable lots of
people, including those who are not
designers by training, to develop
products that are coherent, that fit
into the end-end member experience. I
get really nervous about having
different design languages or different
types of user interactions and shipping
Frankensteins, basically. So, designers
need to then be the people we're hiring
again for design systems thinking. How
do we think about templates and
expression of the brand and what a good
user experience looks like and what is
Netflix and like the Netflix
differentiated special sauce. So,
there's more people on our design team
that have to think that way now than
could I help to design a specific
feature for a specific product. So,
there's this stepping back to look at
the big picture that I think is
happening in every single function and
that requires
some, yeah,
reorientation of skills among the
existing team and also hiring people
who've got that that type of expertise.
And across all of it, it's a mindset
shift. So, we are not hiring people
who are not excited to explore, try new
things, understand lots is changing and
feel comfortable with that ambiguity,
be comfortable that there's a blurring
of how we work and how we partner. It
that's true for people who are already
at Netflix and people who we are adding
to the team that that curiosity
innovation mindset has not
it's not been more important, at least
in the time that I've been working in
this field.
>> On the systems thinking piece, is the
reason this is becoming more important
that it is people are moving so fast
that you need to invest in platforms and
frameworks and and design language and
basically
teach people to fish so they can not be
blocked or is there is there other
reasons?
>> I think it's probably velocity. So
platforms do have a benefit of leverage.
So in general, that that's an
opportunity with or without AI for a
platform to get most teams 80% of the
way there.
And then they don't have to reinvent
those building blocks.
We have more bets that we're making
across the business, more things we're
trying to build. So platform mindsets
are good and it's something that is
relatively more recent for Netflix to
think about that being a real critical
enabler.
There is also the sense of a scaffolding
in a world of AI. So not just the higher
velocity, but you have more people doing
more types of work that are different or
new like we were talking about. And
there's risk that comes with how do you
think about access and identity in that
situation? How do you think about
security in that situation? How do you
think about how shipping high quality
code and design and user experiences?
And so I I don't think it scales well to
have each person who's building
something have to go figure out. Could
you remind me what good looks like here
and what are the bumpers or guardrails I
should keep in mind? I think we need to
encode that in our paved paths and our
ways of working. And for a a data
science or analytical field to encode
here's the source of truth data, here's
how to interpret it, here's how to
access it, here's what to do with it or
not to do with it and to be careful with
certain types of data.
I don't an organization that has
thousands of people can no longer rely
on tribal knowledge or I'm going to find
the one person who knows this. So this
was a challenge that was there before
AI. It's probably a more urgent
challenge with AI and I like the idea of
using AI or any new tech to motivate
like we knew this is work we needed to
do. No time like the present to invest
in that more heavily across the team.
>> I wonder if another reason for this
becoming more valuable is because agents
are now doing a lot of work and giving
them the context, giving them the
scaffolding, giving them the design
language just speeds all that up.
>> Yeah, and one of the visions we have at
Netflix is
we will have so many
agents that are contributing to doing
work that you need to be able to reason
and rationalize throughout that. You
know, the humans are the ones guiding
what's the problem we need to solve. Do
I feel like what we're producing is
impactful and high-quality output?
But the work will be done by both humans
and agents.
And that creates velocity and benefits
and it creates risks. And I think that's
important from especially from an
engineering perspective that we figure
out how to manage that in a way that
lets people move quickly but doesn't
create undue downside or risks for the
company.
>> This connects so directly with
Jenny Wen was on the podcast. She was
head of design for Cloud Code and
Co-work and had this whole design
process is dead kind of thesis and the
pitch there is just there's no time for
design, the design process. And instead
as a designer, you're just kind of
steering people and pointing them in the
direction
and adjusting and also thinking big
picture is when you have the time.
And it feels like that's kind of what
you're describing here is like create
the platform for people to move fast and
then there's no time for like design
process of a specific new feature.
>> I have mixed feelings about that because
I
we do want to enable with infrastructure
and systems thinking more people to do
great work with strong design as part of
it.
Why not take that opportunity that the
new tech provides.
But for our most important priorities,
design is critical
to solve things in the right way. So, we
do still make time for important design
work. We It can move faster. The
designers themselves have more tools in
their toolkit, so they can do incredible
work at a faster velocity, show more
options, learn, iterate, test more
quickly. But I think it would be a
mistake to say
design and deep design expertise and
thinking gets squeezed out just because
we can write code faster. We can do data
analysis faster. That feels like, at
least for a large-scale consumer product
like Netflix, I feel like we would lose
one of the things that makes Netflix
great, which is the product, technology,
and design makes a lot of complexity
invisible, and makes for a seamless
customer experience. That That's a
design mindset that has to be core to
it. So, if the work itself might look
different, but I don't think we lose the
mindset.
>> That's an awesome counterpoint.
So, what I'm hearing is kind of trending
up skills, attributes you look for,
systems thinking, and this kind of
mindset of being comfortable and excited
about change and what's coming and not
being stuck in your own ways.
What are you finding is trending down?
What are you less looking for that used
to value more highly?
>> The days of very narrow, deep
specialization
feel more limited to me.
I can come up with examples where we
still need it because there's an
industry or technology expertise where
there's only a few people in the world
who really know how things work. We have
examples of that on the team for
encoding or how our playback systems
work and things that have been
incredibly innovative and novel for
Netflix. I I still believe we need
specialized practitioners in those
spaces.
But as a general rule, uh compared to 5
or 10 years ago, I I would believe we
have fewer specialists and more people
who are generalists or adaptable in
multiple directions. And that could be
adaptable across functional expertise.
It could be adaptable across flavors of
engineering. So, can I navigate both
back end and front end systems? Can I
hook into infrastructure with a lot of
expertise? I think
the the mindset now needs to be I can
learn that quickly, and that goes back
to the systems thinking. So, I think
specialists can learn to have a broader
array of tools more easily than was true
in the past. So, it we need fewer of
them perhaps because talent's able to
grow in that direction. And there's
something about sticking to a narrow
specialty that maybe triggers for me a
concern about what about the mindset of
growing in different directions and
exploring boring, and I don't want to be
too narrow even in my own assessment of
that, but I it's important that people
who are specialists still have that
sense of I want to try a new way of
solving these problems versus the way we
have in the past.
>> And when you say specialist, are you
thinking like front end, I'm a front end
engineer versus a back end, or are there
other
>> Yeah, or it could be a domain set of
knowledge of Yeah, I'm a deep
>> expert.
>> I'm a payments expert. I'm an
ads marketplace design expert. I'm an an
expert in this very specific tooling
that studio productions use.
>> Mhm.
>> So, there
specialist in subject matter expertise
is an advantage provided that person is
willing to grow and extend into is this
really still the right tool or the right
way to think about the problem? So, I
think it's the layers of the stack from
an engineering perspective that there's
less specialty.
And then
tools that are unlikely to be static or
like to have a lot of inertia around
them. I would think like we would want
people who are able to innovate and
imagine like what's the future version
of this? And so we want more talent like
that.
>> Awesome. So coming back to the systems
thinking piece, people hearing this are
like, okay, I got to work on my systems
thinking
skill set. How do people develop the
skill? Other Is it just do it for a long
time? Work at a lot of complex
projects? Like I think of this book that
everyone always references with the
slinky on the front, Thinking in
Systems.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, how do people learn this?
>> Small trick.
Each
problem you're trying to solve, step out
one click.
Do the like, what am I assuming is true
about the broader space in solving this
problem?
So I was given a task to build some new
feature for the Netflix member
experience.
Let me take one beat and think about
what is the bigger consumer problem
we're trying to solve here?
What's the type of content that this
feature is going to be able to support?
Do I think that the way I was planning
to build this is going to make sense in
a way that scales across multiple
content types? Or it could be something
that's a capability that then is
contributed to a platform set of
offerings for multiple areas.
Is the consumer problem that I'm solving
with this feature
going to be one of the most important
consumer problems that Netflix is going
to need to solve as we have an expanding
world of entertainment and we want to
make it more personalized and immersive.
Those are all questions that like you
don't have to boil the whole ocean. You
don't have to solve for Netflix's
overall strategy and who are we relative
to competition.
But you take the thing you're
responsible for and you just do one zoom
out of the problem you're solving and
question that.
I wouldn't spend too long in the
questioning state because then you're
stuck. Then you're not making forward
progress, but I think that helps people
to think in terms of systems and
question that are we solving the right
problem in the right way that matters
for the end consumer.
>> Another way as you describe it, another
way I'm thinking about it is like think
if you were your manager
how would they what's their broader
perspective across not just your one
team and problem and KPI, but the larger
picture?
>> I've got advice over years that is
similar to that which is
are there ways that I can do my job that
helps
my manager do their job.
And so if I thought about all the things
I'm directly responsible for, but I
thought about it from the perspective of
my manager. So not just product and
tech, but finance and content and other
parts of the business, I would naturally
zoom out and think about how all these
component pieces need to come together
and how the whole could be greater than
the sum of the parts. I think that's
useful thinking. And for engineers to
think about how do I leave a better
version of these systems? How do I think
about the thing that's going to be high
quality and scale for others? There's
both a how do I help my manager and
there's how do I help my colleagues,
which is a core part of some of our
engineering principles of
do the thing that is right for the
broader organization instead of just
what's right for you locally. That's
systems thinking as well. So it's not
just seniority, but it's breadth of the
way I solve this problem and I build
this, is it going to be useful to my
colleagues and am I going to leave a
stronger version of things for the
future set of innovations that we want
to make?
>> That is an awesome tactical advice. Uh
making your manager's life easier is
always a good a good tactic.
>> Career-wise, several reasons. Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> Following the thread a little bit
I know you all added career ladders and
levels recently. It was like a new thing
you guys used to not have these things.
So kind of all on that thread
what have you added to the career
ladders within this AI world. If
anything that you find you want people
to lean into more, you're looking to
more or or not. Like, did you not change
your career ladders and performance
you know, criteria?
>> So, the way we've approached this so far
is instead of trying to articulate
at each level
exactly how AI changes those
expectations, to instead put an overlay
across all of the talent at Netflix,
people on the team, and those who are
hiring to talk about an aspiration for
AI fluency.
And what that looks like is going to
vary by function. It's going to vary
based on where you are in your career.
That could be what level you're in or
what type of role or persona work you're
doing.
But the aspiration for AI fluency, which
is a tough thing to define.
So, does it mean that I have an
experimentation mindset? Does it mean
that I know where AI is useful and not
useful? Does it mean that I've actually
built things using AI? I feel like the
the way that has shown up in career
ladders and how we talk about it evolves
almost by the quarter, if not month or
day, because the tech itself is
advancing so much. So, the most useful
thing is not to make it level specific
or role specific, but to encourage
everyone towards the expectation on AI
fluency, which doesn't mean use it as a
tech for the sake of tech. It's tech
where it's useful, to have good judgment
about that, and to have the mindset to
be open-minded to explore and try new
things. That's the non-negotiable for
all roles, and that's true at the senior
most levels of of Netflix, where we talk
about we too need to have deep fluency
in AI, even if we're not writing code as
part of our day jobs. So, that's that's
changed, and then that's showing up in
our hiring practices as well. Getting
comfortable within interviews exploring
how are people thinking about AI or
technology? What are they using in their
day-to-day or their current job? How
comfortable are they with change and
exploration? And even for things like
coding interviews, allowing candidates,
of course, to use AI tools because
that's going to be part of what the work
requires now. So, those have been shifts
that we've made, but I I doubt it's a
shift that's done versus we're right in
the middle of it.
>> And she's going to keep following this
thread. Obviously, AI is transformative
for coding.
It's a big unlock for prototyping.
Are there other
use cases of AI at Netflix that have
been really impactful that people may
not
think about or not realize?
>> So, there's two that come to mind. So,
the first is
data analysis, distillation of
information, modeling, which is, you
know, get using the tools to get our
arms around all the insights we have,
similar to what I mentioned before. What
experiments have we run? What are the
metrics that I should be looking at for
a certain problem? What's the consumer
research that we've done?
And that is much higher velocity and
much higher quality,
contingent on
you check that the results are valid,
you work with your local data scientist
and am I using the source of truth data
on this?
But, that's been a great one and that's
one personally that I would say I most
use some of these tools for. So, that
goes beyond prototyping and coding to
general analytical thinking and
translating data to action and insight.
The other one is on the
content production, creation part of the
business, which has lots of
applications. This was true before
GenAI. So, ML and AI were deeply used in
a lot of the production tools. We've
used them to think about how to create
promotional assets at scale, how to
localize in subtitles and dubs. So,
GenAI is a big step function in where
the impact can be in creative ideation.
We call those things like
pre-visualization or basically bringing
a creator's vision to life before you
even get into the you bring people to a
set and start to actually go through the
production itself.
There's lots of use cases in
post-production.
So we recently acquired a company Inner
Positive that was started by Ben Affleck
that built a set of models and
capabilities that allow you after you've
shot something to relight, reframe,
reshoot, change dialogue in ways that
are very impactful to get higher quality
content are still led by the filmmaker
creator saying, you know what? I would
like to try something else to bring this
vision to life. But that impact is
extremely promising and we're seeing
lots of productions
leverage different tools, some of them
built in-house, some of them that we
enable through other vendors for those
content creation use cases. And then as
we think about how content comes to the
product, I mentioned localization,
subtitles and dubs, but also how we
create high-quality trailers, images,
artwork at scale that then we can use to
help make sure that titles find their
audiences around the world. Those all
are huge levers when we think about the
AI impact. So that that again goes well
beyond prototyping or coding to some of
the creative use cases and you can
imagine that just like they work for
studio productions for film and TV, they
work for advertising, they work for
marketing, off-service campaigns and so
those are all areas that we're
exploring.
>> This episode is brought to you by
Mercury, radically different banking
loved by over 300,000
entrepreneurs. And now with Command.
I've been a customer of Mercury's for
over 6 years. I have never once thought
about leaving. Mercury is basically what
happens when banking is built by product
people, not by bankers. They make it so
easy, dare I say fun, to send invoices,
move money around, set up virtual cards
for folks on my team. Does your bank
have an API, a terminal native CLI, or
an AI-ready MCB server? I don't think
so. And just recently they launched
command, a conversational interface
built directly into Mercury, which acts
as your financial operator. I've been
using command to transfer money around,
to figure out what categories I've been
spending the most money in, analyze my
cash flows. And [music] just today I
used it to find out how much I've made
from a specific sponsor over the past
year. I just asked, "How much have I
made from X over the past year?" 10
seconds later I have an answer. It is so
freaking cool. Visit mercury.com to
learn more and apply online in minutes.
Mercury is a fintech company, not an
FDIC insured bank. Banking services
provided through Choice Financial Group
and Column NA, members FDIC.
>> You mentioned how Netflix has been very
early to AI and ML for a long time. Uh
younger people may not remember this,
but y'all had this contest to optimize
things.
Yeah. Yeah, the Netflix prize. Like like
just showed an example of how early you
were to AI and ML. People There was I
think it was a million-dollar prize to
optimize the Netflix ranking algorithm a
little bit. Like whoever could optimize
it the most. And I think the winner
optimized it by a few percentage points,
something like that. And it was like the
a huge deal. All these super smart
people got around around the world. Uh
and it happened a few times, right?
>> I mean, you said it on my behalf. Um
often when there's questions about how
is Netflix thinking about AI, it's great
to remind people of exactly that point,
that this is not new to us, that
especially for personalization, it's
been central to delivering a great
experience to members. It's impossible
to take the breadth of content that we
have. There's ever more content. That's
one of the challenges we face.
And make discovery easier and easier and
easier, which is one of the challenges
that Netflix has.
And using AI and ML has been a way to do
that. You want to personalize right
title for the right person at the right
moment, that problem gets harder. The
The more exciting our catalog gets, the
greater breadth of content we have, not
just film and TV, but games and live and
podcasts,
personalization becomes even more
important in what that experience is.
So, we can take a lot of that history
and say, "Okay, well, now how do we
solve this problem?" Because the tech is
even more powerful, but it gives us a
running head start in being clear about
the problem to solve, how important it
is that Netflix solve that for our
members. And then the same is true, as I
was mentioning, on the creative side of
the house. AI and ML have been in things
like visual effects or in localizing
language for a long time. Now we say,
"What's the next era of that when the
tech is more powerful?"
And in In both cases, it ends up taking
a strength that Netflix has, which is
marrying entertainment and technology,
and making sure we stay ahead of the
game to deliver things that are even
better. So, I I love that it it's part
of our history. It still continues to be
a strength, and it's going to have to be
a strength, given the size of the
challenges we're facing around the
breadth of entertainment while keeping a
great experience.
>> Yeah. And I I love that back then it was
called machine learning, and AI was
like, "No, no, this It's not AI. AI is
Never never never Never going to happen.
It's just machine learning."
>> Well, then all of a sudden we call
everything AI, and some of it's machine
learning.
>> That's right.
>> So, I
>> [laughter]
>> I I tried to You know, it depends like
the thing that is of the moment to
describe. So, I think we bucket all of
it as AI now.
>> Yeah, AI has become
>> of AI use cases that are not generative
use cases. So, we could go down a deep
dark hole of all the specific things.
But in general, like I don't think it
would surprise anyone that Netflix is
using a broad array.
And it with so much excitement about
what's possible, the fun thing at
Netflix for the people who work here is
that if you're really passionate about
the applications of tech for
creative outlets, for consumer products,
for infrastructure, we have all of those
problems and AI is at the center of them
and it's good not to forget that that
that's true even if Netflix isn't
branded as an AI company. AI is a tool
that we're very comfortable using to get
these great entertainment and technology
outcomes.
>> The other really interesting thing just
to kind of keep complimenting Netflix
here. If you look at the early culture
deck of Netflix and also our
conversation last time,
things that emerge from that are things
like high agency. This is like something
core to Netflix in the beginning. High
agency, autonomy, high talent density,
very bottom-up thinking, super quick
experiments and launching, paying top of
market. Uh
this is all stuff that every AI like
this is what I hear constantly now from
how the top AI labs operate. So we're
all ending here and this is where
Netflix has been forever.
>> Yeah, it's a little prescient in
understanding what makes talent
incredible.
I've thought about all those aspects of
the culture at Netflix as this is going
to sound a little bit nerdy, but
excellence as an operating system.
So the goal of all those cultural
elements wasn't the end goal in
themselves. It wasn't let's just make
sure people have as much responsibility
as possible or let's you know, we don't
like process. So let's make sure that we
don't have any of that.
It was instead a very strongly held
opinion that that you get to excellence
by giving people a lot of agency and
accountability. By pushing decisions as
deep in the organization as possible,
hiring great people who can be trusted
to have good judgment and make good
decisions.
And that ends up driving incredible
outcomes plus a lot more motivation and
sense of responsibility. It means every
person on the team can feel like I'm
being given
a lot of keys and a lot of
accountability for what happens here and
I myself feel like when you know you're
carrying that level of trust and
accountability, you want to do your best
work.
And so there's something that
feels very intuitive about Netflix's
culture has always been aiming at
excellence.
And when you have great talent and you
give them the ability to do their best
work without micromanaging it or
drowning it in process, you actually get
much better outcomes.
And so I do think that the newer era
companies are picking up on something
that is feeling very familiar to us. And
it it's not something that comes easily.
So having culture is not a static thing.
Culture needs to
grow and evolve as a company gets
bigger, the types of problems you're
solving change. But the notion that like
we're going for excellence and trusting
that exceptional talent needs to be able
to do their best work. That's unchanged
and something that I think continues to
be a special sauce for us.
>> I love this concept, excellence as an
operating system.
It's very uh systems thinking, he he
might say,
for how to set up a company.
>> Exactly, Lenny.
>> [laughter]
>> So for people that like everyone
listening to this will want excellence
as an operating system. Like who would
not want this?
Uh it'd be helpful for people to hear
what are kind of the ingredients to make
this happen. One is obviously high
talent density, just hiring only the
best. Two is accountability. Kind of
there's like the input and the output
essentially. Uh input amazing people,
top the top people, give them make them
accountable, give them autonomy. What
would you say kind of like the pillars
of creating this
uh excellence as an operating system if
people if founders are listening to this
like I want them to do that.
>> Well, the talent density is the
non-negotiable. Like you have to start
with that. If you don't have that, you
can't get to a place where you have
confidence in decision-making at all
levels of the organization,
allowing people to take risks and
innovate quickly. That's a big part of
excellence in the Netflix culture, which
is being very comfortable with
risk-taking.
We don't try to avoid failures, we try
to recover quickly when we have them.
I think there's been great examples of
that. Our foray into live was a
wonderful example of being comfortable
taking a ton of risk, knowing it would
be imperfect, knowing we would learn
fast, and we would be better for it.
I've never been prouder of the team
seeing how we worked through that. So,
you have to be talent density,
comfortable that people are going to
take the context that you give them,
strong judgment and risk taking,
and fight for the things that are the
best outcomes for the business.
You have to be very clear that what
you're doing is driving outcomes for
consumers and Netflix.
So, it's Netflix matters, Netflix
members matter. It's not about my own
personal success or what I prefer. So,
there's a selflessness
that is part of this excellence
operating system.
And then the other thing I would say is
some of the things that are they're
really unnatural for humans to do. So, I
could give a couple examples of things
to get comfortable with,
which is
there are certainly days where I see
decisions happening, and I think, "Hmm,
I would make a different decision."
Like, is that really going to be the
best thing?
But, my job, especially in the Netflix
culture, is not to step in in every one
of those cases and overrule or veto or
question someone,
especially if it's
it's not material, it's not going to
burn the place down. Let people make
that decision and learn from it. And ask
for those reflections afterwards of
like, "How did it go? Maybe I was wrong.
Maybe the decision was a great one."
But, that it's related to the risk
taking and the like help people learn
how to feel comfortable making their own
decisions, especially when they're not
all going to be the right decisions, and
they're going to learn something tough
from it. I felt that myself from my boss
and my peers saying, "This is your
decision. You know, I can provide input.
I can help you brainstorm. It's yours in
the end."
And I that it it just doesn't come
naturally when the stakes are high, when
I feel responsible for what the org's
doing to let people lean into risk can
be uncomfortable.
And I think that also means in cases
where things are not going well as
another example to not assume that
process is going to fix it.
So, if
or something I've learned over the past
few years, that
when planning is difficult, I've never
heard someone say like, "Oh, we figured
out the perfect way to plan."
Or the perfect way to go through
feedback and leveling and compensation.
But every time we saw that and we added
more process, we spent more time without
getting better outcomes.
And so, it's another unnatural thing
that I think everyone's inclination when
things are hard and complicated
is
you think you're simplifying the problem
by putting a lot of constraints around
it,
but it actually goes against the like,
is there a more creative way
to plan or to make people decisions or
to make prioritization decisions that
actually get us to better outcomes. And
so, it's a resistance to do the thing
that a lot of bigger companies would do
and to feel comfortable in that
discomfort very often. So, that's
something I feel in my role and I I
would believe a lot of people at Netflix
feel it because you try not to do the
thing that is
standard.
>> It's easy to say that and hear that, but
I so know what you mean, where somebody
screws up and you're like, "Okay, what
was the thing that went wrong? Let's put
a process in place to avoid this from
happening." And what you're saying is
like, you need to resist that.
Uh because that slows things down and
the best people don't want to be working
in a place with all these checklist and
process and gates and things like that.
>> No, I think the best people want to know
there's going to be a blameless retro
and they're going to feel so
individually responsible
that they're going to say, "How do I
make sure this doesn't happen again?"
Not with process, but with like how
could I share these learnings? How could
I do work differently to make sure that
I get to a better outcome next time?
When you are trusting people to take
those reflections
and learn and grow
I think you get much better
outcomes over time. You get a much
stronger team, which I think is part of
our role as leaders of like you're
you're trying to grow a team that is
resilient and durable and knows how to
have great impact. You're not trying to
control everything.
>> Which is a key to building a team with
high talent density.
There's two sides to this that I want to
chat about briefly. One is the hiring
and the other is
keeping the people. So you're famous for
the keepers test. We talked about this
last time. Another unnatural thing for
people.
People that want to understand what this
is, they can listen to the first
conversation, but has that How has that
evolved over the last couple years?
That's still core part of the culture,
this idea of the keepers test?
>> It's often cited in a way where you
think of keepers test as
that moment where you decide to let
someone go, that they're not the right
fit for the role and the conversation
about that.
But it's equally commonly used to have a
conversation about how extraordinary
someone is.
How well they're doing in a role.
Because it the entry point is for me to
say to one of my direct reports or for
them to say to me
"How am I doing on your keeper test?"
And
the lion's share of the time my response
is, "I would fight so hard to keep you."
Let me go through a set of things that I
think you're doing such a great job at,
what your strengths are, where you're
having a lot of impact. Here's how you
could be even better. So it's an entry
into a conversation that is very
positive and uplifting for people, but
the framing is, "Do I pass the keeper
test?" And then, of course, there's the
harder situations where
I'm evaluating does someone pass the
keeper test or they're asking me, and
it's This is the toughest thing to say,
to be honest, you're not passing that
right now.
I think you could get there in some
cases, and that comes with feedback and
what are those milestones? Or in some
cases you're saying, we've really tried
and I don't see the path to success. So,
it it's just it's an anchor and an entry
point for a conversation that can go
lots of different directions. And the
thing I like about it is it's good
hygiene on feedback and checking in on
how things are going
and forcing a tough conversation
sometimes instead of shying away from
it. Or to keep great talent, you do need
to say you're doing great. Like that
that's an important part of making peo-
people feel recognized and valued. So, I
don't want it to come across that we
just have this
very negative view of it. I think
there's this positive side of the coin
as well.
>> Awesome. I guess just to explain to
people what this is so they don't have
to go listen to other podcasts, I'll try
to briefly explain it. The idea here a
part of the Netflix culture is that
when you have people reporting to you,
you should always be thinking, if I were
to would I hire this person today?
Knowing what I know about them, and if
not, then I should probably let them go.
And the idea there is to keep the high
bar, to not ever just like settle, okay,
this person they're here, I guess we'll
keep them around. Is that is that
roughly the way to understand it?
>> Yeah, and the way it it can it's sort of
a corollary to that if that person came
to me today to say they were leaving,
would I fight to keep them or not? Or
would I say, if if my sense is relief
of, oh yeah, it probably would be better
to have someone else in this role, I
should have taken action in having that
conversation sooner.
>> I love
as you said, it's such an so many
uncomfortable things you have to do to
maintain
>> Yeah, it's the Well, the keeper test is
one, maintaining talent entity, context
not control among leaders. We talk about
being highly aligned but loosely
coupled, which is where light process,
you know, the minimum to make sure we're
clear on the priorities and we can
execute them as what we're solving for.
All of these things are not things that
human beings or organizations at scale
tend to do. So, it's constant diligence
to try to maintain the thing that's made
Netflix a special place. Cuz in the end,
it's the work and the culture that
attracts people and retains people, and
we need that to be a successful
business.
>> So, that's exactly where I was going to
go. Uh so, to make this work, you need
to attract the best people. It's always
been very hard to attract the best
people. Feels insanely hard these days
with the amount of dollars flying
around, the fancy AI labs, so much
competition. There's like everyone's
just, you know, it's it's crazy. What
have you found to be uh effective in
convincing the top people to still come
to Netflix and and join versus all the
other fancy places they can go?
>> Yeah, we've always had a lot of
competition for talent. It might feel
more pronounced right now, but we we
have great talent on the team. Maybe
that goes without saying, but I feel
like I should say it out loud cuz I
believe it. We have incredible talent at
Netflix, recent hires, long-tenured
people.
I'm always impressed by the work that
the team is doing. So, I don't feel like
we've suffered or like other companies
are vacuuming up all the good people
because so many of them I do think sit
at Netflix.
It does feel like we have to be more
more explicit about the types of people
and talent that tend to thrive at
Netflix versus other companies like some
of the frontier labs.
So, people at Netflix have to be
passionate about the application of
technology. And the application or
building products to solve a certain set
of problems. You have to love
entertainment. You have to love consumer
products at scale. You have to love the
global nature of that.
There are a lot of incredibly talented
people
who love that sweet spot. I am one of
them between
tech and product and entertainment and
how do you make those things come
together in a way that's remarkable?
And you use AI to do it. You use other
technologies and products to do it. But
that has to be something that drives you
to be really excited about a lot of the
roles at Netflix.
If instead you're by some of the
foundational work that the frontier
model companies are doing, which is
exciting in its own way, it's a
different persona. It's a different like
here's the problem space that I want to
work in.
But I don't think there's a shortage of
people who get really excited about the
applications of the technology and see
the connection to that to things that
they love and use every day like
Netflix. And so that, you know, that
gets me up in the morning and I think it
gets a lot of the team members up and we
have this conversation about like that's
something special that only talent at
Netflix can do or fill in the blank for
another industry that's deep in the
application of it. I think that's
inspiring.
>> I want to kind of touch on a couple
things that I've been thinking about in
this world of AI that we're uh
approaching. One is uh junior people.
It feels like everyone's like there's a
good example. You're hiring a lot of
awesome senior people that have proven
they're awesome and you know, high
talent density, high bars. Uh
also just AI makes it so easy to do
stuff that people may not be learning
how to do anything. They're like junior
engineers I'm thinking or junior PMs,
junior designers.
Like there's just like how do new people
become these awesome senior people? Is
there anything you've
you think about? Are you hiring junior
people? How do you think about this if
this what happens with junior people not
necessarily learning or having a path to
learn to become the senior person?
>> We are still hiring junior people and
they're really important to our talent
strategy.
So, we still have an intern program, we
still have a new grad program, which is
a was new for us as of a few years ago.
So, prior to a few years ago, we were
only hiring more experienced talent
across all the functions. Now, we do
hire people straight from undergrad and
graduate programs and we'll continue to
do that. So, even in a world of AI where
some things are easier, we were talking
earlier about
mindset, AI fluency.
From my experience,
younger folks are more open-minded.
They tend to be more native in some of
these new ways of working. For a company
that like Netflix, they're also very
fluent in how entertainment is changing,
how consumer behaviors are changing, how
product and tech is influencing that in
the products that they're using. That's
really important to have on our team.
So, there there's the part of the
persona, which is who are you as a new
grad who's an engineer, but there's also
who are you as someone who's in their
early 20s and has a perspective on the
world that is highly valuable and a
comfort with the way the world is
changing. So, that's why I say it's a
critical part of our talent strategy.
To the Okay, so you step into the role
and you have AI tools that didn't exist
5 or 10 years ago, I would say mastery
of the craft is still very important.
So, going back to as the team member,
I'm responsible for the quality of code
that I am submitting for production, I'm
responsible for the quality of products
that I'm building, how they are
designed, what that user consumer
experience is. None of that is going
away. So, if I think about more junior
or earlier career talent on the teams,
we need to be investing just as much in
the mentorship of this is what good
looks like, this is how you use these
tools, but you still take accountability
for what the outcomes are, what the
quality of the output it
And I think I mentioned this earlier, I
find that mastery and that craft
excellence scarce still. So, we want to
make sure we're teaching that. I I think
it's a valid concern of like, how do I
get that if I'm not as hands-on as I
would have had to be, but you still
carry responsibility for reviewing code,
testing code, being able to diagnose
problems, knowing what a good product
looks like. Like, I think that's a very
scarce skill to say, "This is excellence
in in a product that solves a problem
that matters and in how it's designed."
So, I don't think that craft mastery,
the importance of it, is going away.
Probably the way we train and grow
talent has to change cuz they're going
to use different tools, and I can
guarantee you that earlier career talent
is going to be teaching older folks like
me many new things, too. So, I think it
goes in both directions.
>> Where do you think engineering goes in
the I don't know, 5, 10 years? Do you
think
people need to still understand code? Or
do you think there's this abstraction
layer that sits on top where you don't
even have to learn C++, Java, Python,
whatever?
>> I think there's a difference between
being able to write lines of code in a
particular language like Python or C++
and understanding how code, computer
systems, products work.
And I don't think the latter is going
away.
Because if we trusted agents to know all
the languages and write all the code,
we're not going to know
why is something Is it a good product?
Is it a bad product? Is it working as we
expected when it doesn't? Like I
mentioned earlier, we take a lot of
risk. We fail fast, we recover fast.
That requires an understanding of how
are these systems working. I might use
an agent to help me understand those
things, help me detect an anomaly or
something that's broken faster and
triage it,
but I still need to have a fluency of
like, what is this thing that we're
building and how does it work? So I know
if it's good and I know how to fix it.
I don't know I I hope that doesn't go
away cuz it you know, that that's like a
how do we make the world a better place
through the stuff that we're building? I
think requires some understanding of
what we've built.
>> What I'm hearing which it makes sense is
you may not have to write the code but
you have to understand it and what's
happening. But it's so much harder to
just as a person not writing it to
actually you know, have that instilled
in you.
>> I think that's one of the the things
that the learning curve is very steep on
right now. So looking at some of the
code that some of these models or agents
are writing
they're very hard to follow.
It's like I know I'm getting better
performance from this but I have no idea
why and if this thing breaks I'm going
to have no idea how to fix it.
That that's makes me uncomfortable. You
know, maybe that's because I'm still on
that learning curve of like how do we
operate in that world? Like what's the
set of tests or rationalization and
understanding that we need to have to
get comfortable with it? But at first
glance it looks very unfamiliar and very
unsettling. So I think engineering over
time will evolve to be comfortable with
that and have fluency in it and know how
to guide new tech and agents and new
capabilities to make sure that we feel
really good about what the output is.
>> I wonder what the metaphor is for this
where this like it's I continue to be
astounded by how much engineering has
transformed in like 2 years. It's like a
completely different drop down. You're
just used to sit there and then I would
write code and now you're just
talking to agents and reviewing code and
shipping a bunch PRs a day.
>> It feels like it's a it's an
acceleration of how much engineering has
changed. But if you looked over the last
10 years or 20 years you would say the
same thing.
>> Mhm.
>> So it there's just something that's
moving faster and it's hard to wrap our
heads around how quickly it's moved in
the past couple of years but it's not
it's not totally unfamiliar that
engineering or data science or product
would have these big shifts, just like
how filmmaking works. If you will go
over the last 100 years, it's
unbelievably different because of
technology and new tools that we brought
to it.
Just feels like the cycle is speeding
up.
>> Okay, I want to talk about entertainment
for for a brief moment. Just
I'm curious just like how entertainment
will change over time and say like 5, I
don't know, 5, 10 just you know, today
we open up Netflix, check out some
shows, watch some videos. It hasn't
changed in a while, just that idea of
like cool, I'm going to watch the pit
and watch it all. I'm going to watch a
movie. Uh I got TikTok, I got Instagram
feeds of stuff. Like how much different
do you think this will be in I don't
know, 5 years?
The way we entertain ourselves.
>> it's already changing at Netflix
because entertainment is not going to be
one thing in the future and it's already
not one thing now. So, part of the
reason that we are going beyond film and
TV in our offering
is because there's there's an
expectation that consumers have of much
greater variety across formats, devices,
moments of the day that Netflix needs to
be able to serve well in order to meet
consumer expectations and hopefully
exceed them over time. So, when we think
about the addition of mobile and TV or
cloud games
live content podcasts, working with a
broader set of creators who are now on
the Netflix service
all of those things create a greater
breadth of what entertainment is and
Netflix is able to define and expand
that.
And it puts a higher bar expectation on
how do we make sense of that for a
Netflix member?
So, how do we show you this very
seamless journey from I listen to the
Bill Simmons podcast to I watch
Quarterback because I love that as one
of the Netflix offerings in the more,
you could say, traditional film or TV
space
to I play the most recent FIFA cloud
game.
And I want to be able to do that in both
TV and on my mobile phone because now
I'm on the move and I want to be able to
discover and engage with the content at
different moments of the day.
That's already a journey that we're
building into Netflix, which I think
will become stronger and stronger over
time.
So, the future of entertainment isn't
going to be one thing and it's going to
have to be more personalized, more
immersive, more interactive with this
sense of this is a world that I can
explore in lots of different directions
depending on what I'm looking for in the
moment. And that the challenge Netflix
has is we've got to make discovery and
engagement much easier than it feels
today. We have tons of content and it
can feel very fragmented, especially
when you consider all the services or
offerings out there.
And I I think Netflix is very well
positioned to understand how to solve
that problem across entertainment,
product, and tech.
>> The other element of this is AI,
obviously. As an outside observer, it's
like so interesting to see how in tech,
it's like AI, I love it. It's the
future. It's the best. In Hollywood,
it's like, "No. Shut it down." There's
>> There's a mix. There's a very wide
array. So, we Netflix's role in this is
to enable creators with whatever tools
they want to use to bring their vision
to life.
There are going to be some creators or
filmmakers who are on the end of the
spectrum that says, "Absolutely not. No
AI. That is not how I do production.
It's not It's not consistent with my
vision."
That's fine. We work with those
creators.
There's other creators
a growing number of them, I would say,
who are very interested in exploring,
"Wait, can these gen AI tools make
something possible that wasn't possible
before?
Can I tell a story in a new way? Can I
make that story higher quality and more
resonant for audiences? Can I do things
that are extra creative and how I think
about bringing a story to life?
And we support them as well, and we
support all the folks who are in the
in-between. And then that's a really
important position for us to be in
again, because entertainment is not
going to be one thing. There's not going
to be one format. I think there's going
to be types of film and TV that feel
traditional, and then there's going to
be entirely new formats that
unbelievable creators help to bring to
life, and Netflix wants to participate
in that. Which means we need to have a
flexibility in the tools that we provide
and the types of partnerships we have,
and to really have a creator enablement
view rather than a prescriptive that we
only do this one way.
>> I think people are going to be surprised
by just how good AI content is. Like
Spencer Pratt's videos are just like
everyone's like, "Wow, this is
entertaining." Obviously AI, but it's so
interesting. Do you think Do you think
we'll get to a place where it's just
like whole TV shows are AI and people
love it?
>> I have a hard time picturing
entertainment that doesn't have humans
at the heart of it. So that that's
humans in the creation of the
storytelling, which I think is
a scarce and valuable skill. Yeah,
storytelling is
one and the same with humanity.
And like knowing what connects with
people.
So I think humans will be part of the
always be a core part or a critical part
of the story.
And I think
watching
watching characters on screen who don't
have that humanity
feels less compelling to me.
And what the power of storytelling
really is, to like see another human and
to watch how they perform a role or like
bring an emotion to life. That's such a
human element. Will AI help to bring
that to life?
Will play a material part in some of
those productions or how we get them to
look and feel a certain way?
Yeah, definitely.
But I don't see the version of it that
doesn't have the human as the backbone.
>> There's a quote that I think is
misattributed to Salman Rushdie, which
is when a child is born, they first ask
for food and water and projection, and
then they ask for tell me a story.
>> It's a thing going back
since the beginning of time
that storytelling has been a key part of
community and social networks and human
feeling and connection.
So, I love the idea that technology can
amplify that and can bring that to life
in very new, novel, exciting ways.
But, if
to say storytelling wouldn't have that
humanity at the center feels
like something would be missing.
>> Mhm. We're going to see some wild
over the years coming out of this.
>> Oh, I'm sure. There's no question about
that. And a lot of it could be very
entertaining.
You know,
I I don't debate that, either. But, I
think there's going to be a broad range,
and I think Netflix needs to be at the
center of shaping that and bringing that
to life, which is our plan.
>> Amazing.
Well, we covered a lot of ground,
Elizabeth. Uh before we get to our very
exciting lightning round, is there
anything else that you wanted to share,
leave listeners with, maybe double down
on from things we've talked about?
>> It probably came across throughout, but
I I would underscore that this is a
really exciting time to be building
products in entertainment.
Everything we talked about of like
what's changing in the tech and
consumers and like what is entertainment
we're at this unbelievable high-velocity
innovation period. So, it's what keeps
me at Netflix. I think it's a fun place
to be. I would be missing something if I
didn't reinforce that I think that's
true.
Um I also think that as an industry we
spend a lot of time sometimes talking
about the the pure tech or the the
capability
and we sort of lose the forest for the
trees. We're trying to build great
consumer products that people love.
We're trying to make great entertainment
that people love. And it's their
favorite thing that I don't want that to
be lost in Of course, there's amazing
tech and product stuff that sits
underneath, but in the end, the thing
that's most inspirational is what do we
bring to people around the world?
>> And on those lines, there's been such a
uh
the opposite of glut, a drought of
consumer new consumer products, consumer
experiences. Like there's very few
success, like almost no consumer startup
works. Uh and AI feels like an
opportunity for something else to work
and I feel like Netflix is one of the
rare companies and brands that continues
to deliver an awesome consumer product
and business. There's just not that many
of them.
>> Yeah. We're going to keep that up.
>> Well, with that, we reached our very
exciting lightning round. We've got five
questions for you. Are you ready?
>> Okay, I'm ready.
>> All right. What are two or three books
that you find yourself recommending most
to other people?
>> I mean, I have to come up with different
books than I said last time.
>> I don't know. But I I think that sounds
great.
>> I still like a good throwback. So, two
that are coming to my mind
Into Thin Air,
Jon Krakauer,
and Liar's Poker, Michael Lewis. So, I I
worked on Wall Street and I like
reminding people what it was like in the
way back time.
>> Favorite recent movie or TV show you
really enjoyed, which is maybe too hard
for someone working at Netflix, but I'm
going to see what comes out.
>> The The list is very long. Um the most
recent I watched, Remarkably Bright
Creatures, after a recommendation from
my mom. It's a tearjerker. Talk about
the human part of storytelling.
>> Favorite product you've recently
discovered that you really love?
>> Critical for my health and well-being,
Eight Sleep.
>> Do you have a favorite life motto that
you often come back to in work or in
life?
>> I often go back to the things that my
parents instilled in me in very early
times. So,
the the risk of repeating, maybe.
First, something good happens every day.
Watch for it.
Even in the most stressful times.
And second, that the last 5% of effort
usually makes all the difference.
>> These are awesome. I They hit They hit
me.
Final question. I don't know what
anything about this, but you mentioned
you're doing some kind of cycling event.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Tell us Tell us what's going on. What
are you doing here?
>> So, my husband and I are doing a trip
where we ride alongside the Tour de
France for the last week of the race.
So, the tour is 3 weeks. The last week
has a lot of mountain stages. So, we get
to ride part of the route each morning
and then watch the race in the
afternoon.
Not for the faint of heart. So, I'm
trying to train up so I can enjoy those
rides. It's supposed to be vacation
after all.
>> [laughter]
>> My god. I love this vacation. We're just
going to a race.
>> I love cycling. I love professional
sports. It's fun to be able to
participate in it.
>> So, is this like racing or you just kind
of try to go as
nonchalantly through the course?
>> You go nonchalantly. But, still there
are I think I mentioned Yeah, it is It's
physically and mentally challenging. And
I you know, it's not a race, but I don't
want to be at the back of the pack. So,
I got to be comfortable enough to hold
my own.
>> Wow. I love how different this is from
your job. And it feels like something
else to do.
>> It's a good balance and it gets me
outdoors and gives me some nice
perspective. So, I'm looking forward to
it.
>> Elizabeth, you are awesome. Two final
questions. Where can folks find you
online if they want to follow you, reach
out for maybe anything that came up? And
how can listeners be useful to you?
>> The best place to find me and some of
the work we're doing or reach out is the
Netflix tech blog, actually, where we're
putting a lot of things that I've been
talking about up there. We're trying to
do a better job communicating about the
fun stuff we're working on. So, that's a
good first stop, usually. Um and then
how listeners can be useful,
try all the new stuff that we're putting
out there.
Um watch the live events, play the
games, have fun with the new vertical
video feed that we have on mobile called
Clips, send us feedback. So, we want to
make it better, and a lot of these
things are new zero-to-one efforts for
us. So, we're trying to get to great and
excellent as quickly as possible.
>> I love that the homework is go watch
Netflix and
>> You can also watch other things, tell us
how we can be better, but I'm I'm
definitely interested in how can we be
better at Netflix.
>> I love it. I'm going to go I'm going to
go do that. Elizabeth, thank you so much
for being here and being here again.
>> Thank you for having me. Always fun.
>> Thank you so much for listening. If you
found this valuable, you can subscribe
to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review, as that really
helps other listeners find the podcast.
You can find all past episodes or learn
more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com.
See you in the next episode.